# Ann M. Cooper-Milne

(937) 213-1611 | amcmilne@gmail.com

## HTML | CSS | Javascript | Node | React | MySQL | MongoDB | IndexedDB | Progressive Web Apps | MERN

## **HIGHLIGHTS**

As an eager and enthusiastic Junior Full Stack Web Developer, I bring my 17 years of experience in healthcare, including the management of two outpatient physical therapy offices. I developed strong communication skills working with both patients and staff, which will prove very beneficial when in front of customers and clients. I am confident I can adapt well to any environment, as I have experience in both large organizations and a small PT-own practice.

## **EDUCATION**

#### The Ohio State University College of Engineering, Columbus, OH

Coding Boot Camp, April 2021

- Created a Portfolio app using React, NodeJS, API's, HTML, and CSS.
- Worked on three separate group projects remotely.
- I have nearly 20 projects and assignments completed in the last 6 months, using a wide range of technologies.

#### Clark State Community College, Springfield, OH

Associates of Applied Science in Physical Therapy Assisting, June 2009

#### Wilmington College, Wilmington, OH

Bachelor of Science in Athletic Training, Cum Laude, June 2004

- Green Key Honor Society
- Dean's List 5 consecutive semesters
- Sports Medicine Leadership Council

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Central Ohio Primary Care Sport, Spine, & Joint, Westerville, OH

Physical Therapist Assistant, Athletic Trainer

February 2018-present

- Maintained an open line of communication with referral sources and their medical staff.
- Daily schedule management to ensure all patients are seen in a timely manner.
- Documented treatments in an electronic medical records system.

## SpineFirst Physical Therapy, Columbus OH

Physical Therapist Assistant, Corrective Exercise Specialist

September 2015 to October 2017

- Played an integral role in restructuring the business model, including change of ownership and rebranding.
- Implemented an electronic medical records and billing system.
- Assisted in the hiring and training of a new lead physical therapist.
- Established and maintained relationships with referral sources throughout the restructuring/rebranding process.
- Facilitated the credentialing process with several insurance companies.
- Trained staff on proper billing/coding to optimize reimbursement.
- Collaborated with other local healthcare providers to promote continuity of care during the restructuring process.

Ann Cooper-Milne amcmilne@gmail.com (937) 213-1611

#### NovaCare Rehabilitation, Columbus, OH

Site Supervisor, Physical Therapist Assistant, & Athletic Trainer

September 2005 to September 2015

- Managed 6 employees across two clinics.
- Established and maintained multiple referral source relationships in a highly competitive market..
- Maintained an open and direct line of communication with all referral sources.
- Completed weekly reports to update staff on budget metrics.
- Reviewed monthly clinic budget and compiled operational reports for middle management.
- Attended monthly market-wide management meetings to review goals and financial standings.
- Held monthly staff meetings to review financial standings, market changes, and best practices.
- Completed internal medical chart audits.

## Osborn Chiropractic, Columbus, OH

Chiropractic Assistant

September 2004-September 2005 Certificate, April 2021

## PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

- OTPTAT Board Physical Therapist Assistant Licensure- PTA007344
- OTPTAT Board Athletic Trainer Licensure- AT002456
- BOCATC Certification Athletic Training- 080402376
- AHA Advance BLS CPR & AED
- Smart Tools Plus
- Integrative Dry Needling